<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Cruor</name>
        <description>The Cruor race from The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent.</description>
        <author url="https://sites.google.com/view/thearchivistsguide/home">Oroka_</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="Race-Cruor.xml" url="" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Cruor" type="Race" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACE_CRUOR">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Cruor are vampiric beings that were once healthy humanoids but have now been infected with the deadly plague of ruria.</p>
            <h4>SURVIVORS OF RURIA</h4>
            <p>Cruor are survivors of ruria, an extremely contagious disease originating from the Elven continent. It hasn't spread particularly far into the Khyan continent. It usually occurs in edge cases and strangely appears far less contagious than it is in the Elven continent.</p>
            <h4>THE STAGES OF INFECTION</h4>
            <p>The first stage is what's known as turning:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The infected becomes erratic and delerious</li>
                <li>The stage typically lasts 24 hours</li>
                <li>Every 24 hours the infected must make a DC10 constitution saving throw. If they succeed they remain in this stage. If they can last 72 hours (passing 3 saving throws) they become a Cruor. An infected can often go into a seeminly lifeless state after the second day, and should they awake, find themselves in a morgue or tomb, or in the worst cases: buried.</li>
                <li>The infected often acts violently, typically trying to bite people.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>The second stage is when the infected goes beyond the point of no return; their skin becomes grey, their fat disintegrates, their body becoming lithe. The infected grows claws and fangs. The infected is now a mere husk of what they used to be, barely able to form sentences. If still free to move, they scramble about hunched over, sometimes using their arms as well as legs. This stage can last up to a week (1d6+1 days)</p>
            <p class="indent">The third stage is when the infected becomes an incolam. The joints such as the elbows and knees deteriorate to such a state that they can bend in both directions, they run on all fours, their faces sullen and lifeless. The brain is almost completely destroyed. The nose dissipates completely, the eyes sockets become far too large for the eyes, allowing them to shake in their sockets and even fall out in some cases. When many become incolams they are seen to act as a hive mind, but what controls them or induces this behaviour eludes the scientists of the realm.</p>
            <h4>FOREVER CHANGED</h4>
            <p>Cruor are permanently scarred by their time spent infected, both physically and mentally. Whilst retaining the basic appearance of their original race, their skin loses saturation, becoming a shade of grey (there's a wide spectrum of shades amongst the Cruor), their eyes become a bright blood red. Most also find their hair now grows out pure white, although some retain their original hair colour, others hair turning jet black. Cruor grow large fangs where there canines were, the rest of their teeth shifting to acommodate them. They gain the ability to extend claws from their finger nails. Cruor awaken and immediately feel a surge in awareness due to their hightened senses. </p>
            <p class="indent">Mentally, a Cruor can seem distant at first as they adjust to their new form. Many find the taste of normal food disgusting, almost vomit-worthy. Over time vampires can grow to stomach it more, but still rely on humanoid blood as a primary food source. Many cannot take their dependence upon exploiting humanoids and end up killing themselves or simply starving to death. Becuase of this, those who can get past their dependence upon flesh are often unempathic and cold. Although, others often take a different perspective, accepting it as a necessity of their new form. Cruor often find they have an affinity with certain beasts such as wolves, ravens, and the archetypal bat.</p>
            <h4>CRUOR TRAITS</h4>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase</i></b> You automatically get plus 1 to wisdom and can choose to gain 2 in any other ability score of your choice. If you choose wisdom then you get plus 1 on top of the initial bonus and can choose +1 in another score.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Age. </i></b>Vampires don’t mature and age in the same way that other races do. Every living vampire is either a bloodchief, infected by Ulamog’s influence in the distant reaches of history, or was spawned by a bloodchief from a living human. Most vampires are thus very old, but few have any memory of their earliest years.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Alignment. </i></b>Vampires have no innate tendency towards lawful or chaotic, but their need to feast on human flesh means that they are often evil. There are exceptions, but they are few and far between.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Size. </i></b>You retain the size of your original race.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Speed. </i></b>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Vampiric Resistance. </i></b>You have resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Darkvision.</i></b>Thanks to your heritage, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Languages. </i></b>You can speak, read, and write Common and UnderCommon</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Sanguine Diet. </i></b>As a vampire you depend upon humanoid flesh or blood to survive, however, you are sustained for longer. You can go for up to a month without needing blood after having drank some. Eating regular food will sustain you as normal and stop you from starving, however, you become affected by the poisoned condition for the next 24 hours. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>ShapeChanger. </i></b>As a vampire, starting from level 3, you have the ability to turn into certain animals. As a bonus action or when you take the dodge, dash, or disengage action on your turn you can turn into either a Swarm of Bats (or a single bat), Swarm of Ravens (or a single raven), or a wolf. All equiptment you are wearing or holding is absorbed into your new form. You can stay in this form for a number of minutes equal to your level. You can use this ability twice per short rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Natural Weapons. </i></b>You can use your fangs and claws as natural weapons. Your claws and fangs deal 1d6 damage. When you bite someone they must make a constitution saving throw. If they fail they take 2d6 necrotic damage. Moreover, any damage you deal (including the original damage) you recover as hit points. At the beginning of each of your turns after using this roll a d6. On a 5 or 6 you regain this ability. Once recharged, you dont need to roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>A vampiric survivor of ruria</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name='wisdom' value="1" />
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Cruor Ability Score Increase" supports="Cruor ASI" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_WOTC_PSI_LANGUAGE_VAMPIRE" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_SHAPECHANGER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_NATURALWEAPONS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="ShapeChanger" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_SHAPECHANGER">
        <description>
            <p>As a vampire, starting from level 3, you have the ability to turn into certain animals. As a bonus action or when you take the dodge, dash, or disengage action on your turn you can turn into either a Swarm of Bats (or a single bat), Swarm of Ravens (or a single raven), or a wolf. All equiptment you are wearing or holding is absorbed into your new form. You can stay in this form for a number of minutes equal to your level. You can use this ability once per short rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus action / Special " usage=" 2/short rest ">
            <description>As a bonus action or when you take the dodge/dash/disengage action on your turn you can shapeshift into a swarm of bats, swarm of ravens, or a wolf for up to {{trait:shapechange}} minutes</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="trait:ShapeChange" value="level" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Natural Weapons" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_NATURALWEAPONS">
        <description>
            <p>You can use your fangs and claws as natural weapons. Your claws and fangs deal 1d6 damage. When you bite someone they must make a DC14 constitution saving throw. If they fail they take 2d6 necrotic damage. Moreover, any damage you deal (including the original damage) you recover as hit points. If they succeed then they take half damage and you dont receive any health. At the beginning of each of your turns after using this roll a d6. On a 5 or 6 you regain this ability. Once recharged, you dont need to roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage=" Recharge(5-6) ">
            <description>Your fangs and claws deal 1d6 damage. When you succeed on an attack roll with fangs the enemy must make a DC14 CON saving throw. On a fail they take 2d6 necrotic damage and you regain the same amount of hit points (including the original 1d6). If they succeed they take half damage and you dont heal whatsoever. </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Strength)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_ASI_STR">
        <supports>Cruor ASI</supports>
        <description>Your X score increases by 2</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="2" alt="Cruor ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Dexterity)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_ASI_DEX">
        <supports>Cruor ASI</supports>
        <description>Your Dexterity score increases by 2</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" alt="Cruor ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Constitution)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_ASI_CON">
        <supports>Cruor ASI</supports>
        <description>Your Constitution score increases by 2</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="2" alt="Cruor ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Intelligence)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_ASI_INT">
        <supports>Cruor ASI</supports>
        <description>Your Intelligence score increases by 2</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="2" alt="Cruor ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Wisdom)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_ASI_WIS">
        <supports>Cruor ASI</supports>
        <description>Your Wisdom score increases by 1 and you can choose to increase another ability score by 1</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" alt="Cruor ASI" />
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Wisdom Score Increase" supports="Cruor ASI Wisdom" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Charisma)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_ASI_CHA">
        <supports>Cruor ASI</supports>
        <description>Your Charisma score increases by 2</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" alt="Cruor ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Strength)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_WASI_STR">
        <supports>Cruor ASI Wisdom</supports>
        <description>Your Strength score increases by 1</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1" alt="Cruor Wisdom ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Dexterity)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_WASI_DEX">
        <supports>Cruor ASI Wisdom</supports>
        <description>Your Dexterity score increases by 1</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" alt="Cruor Wisdom ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Constitution)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_WASI_CON">
        <supports>Cruor ASI Wisdom</supports>
        <description>Your Constitution score increases by 1</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" alt="Cruor Wisdom ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Intelligence)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_WASI_INT">
        <supports>Cruor ASI Wisdom</supports>
        <description>Your Intelligence score increases by 1</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" alt="Cruor Wisdom ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase (Charisma)" type="Racial Trait" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_RACIAL_TRAIT_CRUOR_WASI_CHA">
        <supports>Cruor ASI Wisdom</supports>
        <description>Your Charisma score increases by 1</description>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" alt="Cruor Wisdom ASI" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Vampiric Assault" type="Feat" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_FEAT_CRUOR_ASSAULT">
        <prerequisite>Cruor</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_OROKA_KHY_RACE_CRUOR</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><i>Prerequisites: Cruor</i></p>
            <p>Your vampiric powers have mutated, growing stronger</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Once per short rest you can teleport up to 30ft away as an action</li>
                <li>As part of the same action you can make a bite attack against a single target within range.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">You can teleport up to 30ft away and as part of the same action make a single bite attack at a target within range.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Creature of the Night" type="Feat" source="The Archivist's Guide to the Khyan Continent" id="ID_OROKA_KHY_FEAT_CRUOR_COTN">
        <prerequisite>Cruor</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_OROKA_KHY_RACE_CRUOR</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><i>Prerequisites: Cruor</i></p>
            <p>Your vampiric powers have mutated, growing stronger</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Once per short rest you can teleport up to 30ft away as</li>
                <li>As part of the same action you can make a bite attack against a single target within range.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">You can teleport up to 30ft away and as part of the same action make a single bite attack at a target within range.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>
